[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome back to the ask abijit show
today we are doing Episode 229 I hope
you're all doing very well and we have a
lot to discuss but as always let me see
who all is there on the live chat here
with us on the live stream I can see
feminist Slayer Mr 88 ombe ker Karthik
da vaj deshmuk dearon bachara
geopolitical dub hello sharat Bagel Vib
Master 99 priyan sud pray Paul from
Kolkata kapalin AAL Gandhi bries SK
Anand borya geopolitic vickram
geopolitical Krishna ragunath from the
suis Netherlands uh geopolitical dub
hello
Narendra despande red Rahul dun space
link metalloids Raja akashkumar
um who else do we have sual kumal konal
ch Mr abijit ilav hatalar zubon eang
johnv sh Shivan Shankar Sami statement
aay Rupal Daria Lavan
SGD uh VI manak ragunath mukarji Shas
Mitra Rahul Manisha MTI vanraj
Sara America is best
vixel phenol abishek haa bat first prar
Gupta Amisha Mishra hello rishikesh Dash
Gupta God
mundan Rajiv Kumar Gupta Aman
oja who else uh gorov jot mam Anonymous
pretam pretam s sh
Wason uh tun Tac Light Yagami Baba
Abhijit
chav and so many other people okay
Nishan tiari and Sindra and Sagar Gare
and abishek pal Singh jnit Singh utsav
katri everybody else okay so let's get
going with the questions that you have
asked in the comments I'll take a bunch
of those and then if there's time I'll
take questions from the live chat uh so
let's go let's go what's the first
question that we have
today the first question is by rori
which animal species except humans if
they were to if it were to suddenly
become extinct would cause an Extinction
event again on Earth and why so what's
an Extinction event an Extinction event
is a catastrophe a biological
catastrophe in which something happens
on the planet which causes a significant
percentage of the life forms or species
on the planet to go completely extinct
so that's a an Extinction event and the
last Extinction event that we know of
happened about 66 million years before
today it was it happened as a
consequence of the um chick Shob impact
event in which a comet or Meteo
meteorite impacted the Earth around
somewhere around the uh the the the
yukatan province region of Mexico and it
killed off the non-avian dinosaurs and
and significant percentage more than 90%
of the species on the planet so that was
the last Extinction event that happened
uh that we know of significant
Extinction event
now
today what one animal
species if it were to go extinct except
for humans would cause an Extinction
event that's a
question uh I would say it would take
more than one ex one animal species to
go extinct one ex I
can one of the most important classes of
animals on the planet are the
phytoplankton and the zooplankton the
coplon are microscopic
plants photosynthetic microorganisms
that uh that live in the oceans and they
produce a significant portion of the
world's
oxygen and the phytoplankton are the
primary producers of oxygen in the
oceans and then you have Z Plankton
which are microscopic animals
microorganisms they feed on the
phytoplankton and then you have fish and
whales and other marine animals that
feed on the zoo
Plankton okay so you have phytoplankton
which are
microscopic plants microorganisms and
you have zup Plankton which are
microscopic
animals these two I would say are
extremely important if the phytoplankton
for example were to go extinct a
significant percentage of the of the
oxygen that's produced on the planet
would no longer be produced and if the
phytoplankton go extinct then the zo
Plankton will very quickly go extinct
because they will have nothing to eat
and then the oceans could turn anoxic
which means that they would not have
sufficient oxygen in them to sustain
other fish and other life forms like
fish and other other various kinds of
animals so you could have a significant
Extinction event happening in the oceans
and if the oceans die then obviously
it's going to cause repercussions on
land because oceans are two3 of the
planet's U uh you know surface area and
then whichever animals mammals Etc feed
on fish and marine life they would start
going extinct so you could have a domino
effect being caused by this so I would
say one of the animal classes of animals
are the Plankton the phop Plankton The
Zo Plankton if they go extinct it's
going to be disaster on planet Earth
another one that I could think of is the
pollinating
insects so on land you have much of the
uh land area of the earth that is which
is covered by uh vegetation plants trees
grasses and all that okay and many of
these are flowering plants and trees and
so on lots of crops for example are flow
flowering crops that we all depend on
humans now these flowering plants and
trees and crops and all they depend on
insect
pollinators so what are insect
pollinators these are insects that go
from flower to flower plant to plant and
to to and they seek uh they seek the
plants
nectar and while seeking the plants
nectar they end up cross-pollinating the
plants so plants they have pollen in
their flowers and when a bee or or any
of any of these insects goes from one
one flower to another it ends up
pollinating the other the other um
flowers the other plants and that is the
process of asexual reproduction that
that plants have so these uh pollinating
insects they obviously we know about
bees everyone knows about bees but they
also we also have flies and butterflies
and beetles Etc these are vital
pollinators and if these were to go
extinct it could cause Extinction events
among the plants and if the plants start
going extinct then we could go extinct
so uh that's what I can think of off the
top of my head uh The Zo Plankton the
phytop plankt first of all the
phytoplankton then the Z Plankton and
the then the third class of uh animals
would be the pollinating insects if any
of these three goes extinct then it's
going to be a disaster on the planet of
on the planet and it could cause a mass
extinction event all right let's go to
the second question for
today ah vac viac everyone's everyone in
India is is uh keeping an eye on on
what's Happening to VI
ramaswami so uh we have questions by we
have a lot of questions I've taken just
four as a representation of everything
that of the questions that everyone
asking everyone is asking Rik PA an
kacha Sun Moon 0877 and Vikram
Ador what are the questions why was Viv
ramaswami sideline is it because of his
skin color or his H1B tweet against the
Americans did he make a political
blender after tweeting on the
controversial H1B topic your opinion on
vivik ramaswami being oued from Doge the
department of government government
efficiency
why is he has he been kicked out from
doge is Elon Musk behind this and once a
prominent contender in the presidential
race VI ramaswami has seemingly faded
from mainstream media with reports
suggesting his removal from do it's
happened yes and a potential sh shift
towards running for governor of Ohio
does this signal the end of his
presidential Ambitions and will the US
ever see a young magnetic leader
irrespective of their background or skin
color is to the presidency so what we
what we are seeing right now is that uh
vivik was supposed to be one of the two
uh Front Runners or one of the two
people who would run this new
organization called Doge do the
department of government efficiency the
other one would be Elon Musk so it would
be like Elon Musk first VI second and
everybody else under these two guys that
is how it was supposed to be and now
it's emerged the news has come out that
Vive ramaswami will no longer be uh
involved in Doge Elon Musk is going to
be the only guy running Doge and VI will
be focusing on uh trying to become
running for the post of governor of Ohio
that's what one hears it's not confirmed
now viik Ras Swami was very active the
past couple of years on Twitter on on
social media on other the forms of media
Etc the past couple of weeks he went
very quiet he went very quiet he was
completely silent on Twitter now he kind
of come back so what happened it all
went wrong for Vi with with his with one
of his tweets the long tweet that he
made about uh I'm not going to open the
tweet and do that but he tweeted about
the H1B
controversy and Trump was in favor of H1
is in favor of H1B immigration and
having the right kind of people coming
in Elon Musk has has been a strong
defender of the H1B uh Visa policy and
VI also defended the H1B Visa policy but
VI
the way he he he formulated his tweet uh
you know it looked like he was uh saying
that Americans have low standards and
they need to do better and things like
that and coming from uh an Indian origin
person a first second generation
immigrant brown skinned guy I don't
think the Americans will take it
especially the conservatives uh the Maga
crowd uh it it really rubbed them off
the wrong way it ruffled their feathers
the wrong way and that I think it was
politically extremely naive and immature
of of viic to lecture his potential
voters see in
in in
politics in in in a democracy at the end
of the day the you've got to depend on
the voter and you want to ensure that
you offend as little of the vote
potential vote Bank as possible POS and
VI went off on the styde against uh the
people who were opposing the H1B Visa
policy and it it it really made a
tremendous number of
people uh among the Republicans angry
and they were waiting for an excuse to
to show off their racism against
non-white people so in the US you know
racism is is not looked upon as
something good you can't say a thing
against uh let's say the black people in
the past the Americans were very racist
against the blacks okay but today you
can't say a thing against the blacks and
I'm I think it's a good thing right
racism is bad you can't say a thing
against Muslims for example you'll be
called islamophobic and you'll be
cancelled but when it comes to Indians
you you can say whatever you want to be
to to Indians and you can be as racist
as you want against Indians because
Indians aren't politically significant
even despite being I don't know three I
don't know about 1% of the US population
Indians haven't Unified as a as a as a
single cohesive political block so
Indians are insignificant politically
and you can just say whatever you want
and there'll be no consequences the
media won't cancel you social media
won't cancel you so uh that's what's
happened VI was incredibly naive in
going after his vote Bank his potential
vote bank I mean think about it in India
Mr Modi the Prime Minister what does he
call the voter uh janata janardan he
does his best to bow to to bend over
backward to appease every section
imaginable of the Indian voting public
right Mr Modi is is obviously he knows
he's an extremely experienced and uh
wise politician it is political suicide
to to to alienate even a certain small
percentage of the potential vote back
you can't do that and VI I don't know
out of what out of immaturity out of
naivity or whatever he just opened the
doors for all his potential haters to
come and you know go after him and I
suppose Trump was just waiting for that
opportunity you know I don't think Trump
likes viic a lot uh he says he likes him
he says that I didn't like him when he
was running against me but now I like
him and all that but you know at the end
of the day it's all about the voter and
when the voter has turned against Viv
Trump's gonna let him go and when it
comes to the Department of govern
government efficiency Doge uh there
could only be one top dog
and Elon Musk is not going to let
another guy try to joust for the number
one spot or even the number two spot
especially when it's a guy like Vive
extremely intelligent extremely sharp
extremely all that so Elon Musk was
waiting for the opportunity to get rid
of Vivic obviously that's how it works
and the opportunity was presented to
them on a platter by Viv himself and
that's what happened uh so we is out of
Dodge he's going to fade out of the
political Limelight to some extent he
may run for governor of Ohio I don't
think it's it's going to be easy for him
to become the governor of
Ohio okay first of all he's brown
secondly he's way more intelligent than
most white people which is like it makes
people insecure thirdly he's not even a
Christian he is still a polytheist he's
still a Hindu if he had at least
converted to Christianity things would
have been fine for him I mean somewhat
easier for him uh like like uh Bobby
Jindal or Nikki Haley they they
converted to Christianity so that that's
why they were able to become governors
of whatever uh Vic he remains a Hindu he
tries to portray himself as an abrahamic
Hindu of sorts I believe in one God a
monotheistic form of Hinduism or
whatever is's trying his best to align
himself with the prevailing uh culture
in the US but it's not going to work I
think uh uh right now next few years VI
is going to fade away but he's still
young he is still very rich so in the
long run who knows things may change but
uh yeah things are looking not very good
for we we right now and for us Indians
how do we care let's say in the future
he could have become president but he
has shot himself in the fo and it's no
longer easy for him even if VI were to
become president in the future what
difference will it make for India it's
going to be America first so I don't
know why Indians are so obsessed with
Indian origin people succeeding outside
of India especially in the US it does no
good to India you had Kamala Harris
Kamala Harris half Indian lady who was
the vi vice president of the US
until four days ago five days ago what
good did she do for India she was
strongly anti-india in her policies
wasn't she and you have Sundar picai and
and and uh SAA nadela all these people
who are CEOs of the biggest companies on
the planet I mean do they do a single
thing that's good for India no they
serve their company and they serve their
Nation they are now citizens of the US
so I don't know why Indians are so
obsessed with Indians succeeding in the
US it makes no difference to India so
from my perspective I don't care you
know VI doing well Vive not doing so
well of course if he does well then the
uh perception of Indians kind of
slightly increases and maybe a lot of
and a lot of hate will then flow towards
India as well so overall it doesn't make
any difference for India from a national
interest National Security perspective
so I I don't care but uh yeah that's the
deal with VI extremely
naive move extremely immature move by Vi
you don't ever lecture your potential
vote Bank you never do that ex that's
that's politics 101 politics 101 you
don't do that and he did the Cardinal
mistake cardinal sin in politics is to
lecture your vote back you never do that
you got to bend over backwards and go to
bow in scrape in front of them that's
what you would do so he it's if he has
has anyone to blame he has only himself
to blame for what's
happened vicam GE political says people
in the US are going crazy over us
citizenships and are even going for
pre-term C-sections cesarian sections so
that their child is born before the 20th
of February is the US citizenship worth
more than your child's health what's
your take on this you know this news
that we are seeing of late on social
media that Indians Indian origin people
are going for are scheduling emergency
cesarian sections to have their child
artificially born slightly premature
before the 20th of Feb because that is a
cut off date for the end of the
birthright citizenship this news is fake
news it has been put out by a couple of
Indian newspapers like the times of
India and the Indian Express if I'm not
mistaken you know and this is entirely
fake news Indian media outlets and
Indian uh yeah Indian media media
Outlets have no journalists on the
ground in the US
all they do is they look at reports from
the Western media and they rehash it in
and say that it's it's our analysis and
our news Indian media is the worst of
the Medias in the
world the most incompetent media in the
world and this is fake news how do they
know that a lot of Indians are doing
this do they have reporters on the
ground in the US who are keeping an eye
and tabs on Indian citizens who are
trying to and what they're trying to do
especially those who are those who have
are from who are pregnant for example no
this is completely fake news and it's
tarnishing India's image in the world
this is the Indian media for you just
for the sake of some sens sensationalism
and and and some breaking news they
don't care what what what their stupid
reporting does to to the IND to the
nation's image worldwide this is
entirely fake
news absolutely fake news it's possible
that if
somebody you know their their kid was
supposed to be born let's say sometime
in March they may try and have a
C-section uh scheduled for before the
20th of February it's possible but do we
have a single instance that is verified
we don't have it have the have these
media Outlets Times of India Etc
given data or statistics that these we
have we have evidence that these many
people are doing that nothing absolute
nonsense absolute fake
news uh I I think it's really
reprehensible that they're doing
this Brar Gupta says within 4 days
within four days of taking over of the
presidency of of America Mr Trump has
taken many phenomenal decisions and
signed executive orders like leaving the
wh deporting illegal immigrants changing
citizenship laws warning of tariffs at
the wef world economic Forum 2025 and
many more what do you think of these is
this just the
Jo of trump or is is it really going to
give does it seriously does it really
give a serious indication of how is
tenor is going to shape up the world is
going to shape the world in the next
four years I don't think it's some new
fangled enthusiasm which will slowly die
down I don't think so Trump means
business and Trump at this time the
difference between Trump as the 45th
president and Trump today is the 47th
president of the US the difference is
that as the 45th president he was
swimming against the current he did not
have the support of the
establishment at
all this time Trump 47 pus 47 has the
complete support of the establishment
the so-called deep state or whatever you
want to call it and
his his clear Ambit is to completely
reshape the
world into a more favorable world for us
hegemony and the US Empire that's what
his his remit is that's what he's going
to do so he's uh he is signed I don't
know how many executive orders on the
first day itself more than 100 more than
200 I'm not sure and he has undone so
many of the policies right on day one of
the Biden
Administration
um and he's just getting started uh
Trump is going to show the world what
real power is and how power is to be
wielded how how power is supposed to be
wielded if you get power in your hands
how do you use power this going to show
the world that not just internally when
it comes to the internal policies in the
US but globally geopolitically he's
going to to show the world that the last
century after 1945 of the so-called
rules-based world order this very nice
period of less Wars and all that um
things don't really work that way that
was an outlier right at the end of the
day it's all about raw naked Power and
that's what he's going to do so he is
already going after Greenland he will go
after Panama he may go after Canada he
may have certain certain plans for India
for China for Russia he is going to be
as subtle Donald Trump is going to be as
subtle and as restrained as a wildf fire
in a library that's how it's going to be
he's just getting
started so the first day right after
taking oath he signs about 200 executive
decisions that completely undo so much
of what Biden and his his government's
policies
were that's how you supposed to do
that's how we supposed to do things once
you get power in your hands you're
supposed to use the power and change
things not continue the same old same
old policies in India we keep on mooning
in India we keep on
mooning well Trump is on day one
changing the system itself that's how
you do it you got to
fight so yeah that's the difference
between Trump and other world leaders I
would say and obviously the system also
is different but that's what you have it
so um so what Trump has done in the past
four days is a serious indication of
what he's going to do to shape the world
in the next four years he's going to be
a transformative president one of the
most impactful presidents um his his
objective probably is to be the most the
big
baddest greatest president in the US
since George Washington I think that's
what his plan is to leave behind that
Legacy that nobody will forget so he's
just getting started believe you
me vicam geopolitical says India has
agreed to take back 18,000 illegal
Indian immigrants from the US how do I
see this move so we know that during the
Biden era four years the past four years
they they opened the the gates of the US
the southern border and they allowed as
many illegal immigrants to flow through
the southern border as they could and
most of these illegals were people from
South America Latin America I don't know
Africa Etc but you also had Indians who
are coming in so all you had to do as an
Indian or any illegal immigrant is that
you at the border you tear up your
passport throw it in in in the bushes or
wherever in the trash and you cross in
and you cross over into the us as long
as you have no official documentation
you'll be taken as a you would be taken
to some place in the US um by bus or by
train or whatever you would be given a
hotel and some money and cash and some
kind of some form of ID and the Biden
regime would try and assimilate you into
the US population as a as a member of a
pro Democrat Democratic party vote bag
that was the
plan so I've seen videos of Indians
crossing the border the US Mexico border
into the US crossing over so it looks
like there are about 18,000 illegals who
have been brought in by Biden and his
regime and uh now Trump wants them gone
well obviously he has the right to do
that if they if they have entered the
the US
illegally uh and when Trump tells the
Indian government I need this to happen
do you think India will say
no obviously India will not say no we
dare not so India naturally will do
whatever we will do whatever we can to
please him and not incur his anger and
wrath so I think it's a smart move it's
it's uh it's not like we have any choice
that's how I see
it and here is the inevitable question
when it comes to repatriation of illegal
immigrants the US is doing that Trump is
going to go all out after this and then
the question is this will the Modi
government 3.0 do anything to overcome
illegal immigration from Bangladesh and
Myanmar from Bangladesh you have
millions of Bangladesh is coming in and
rohinga also and from Myanmar you have I
don't know how many lacks of cookies
just walking into India right it's a
serious issue yeah yeah it's a serious
issue which we need to resolve as the
illegal immigrants are getting involved
in crimes and thefts and as we saw
recently with sa Ali Khan uh I'm from
Assam BJP is doing nothing congress and
BJP are the same both are fooling
Indians I am from jamu and Bangladeshi
people live in jamu and take part in
agriculture in jamu and they open jeice
shops in Jews shops in jamu I request to
the government please ban their fake
Indian other cards
this is this has been going on for so
long about I don't know more than see
the cookie infiltration has been going
on in India since the 20th century okay
uh after 1949 when Manipur officially
became a part of the Indian Union uh the
Indian government's policy was to bring
in cookies as refugees and settle them
in Manipur territory in Indian Territory
why I have no idea why completely
idiotic imbecilic policy moronic policy
do I have worse words I'm sure I do but
I won't utter them here but that's what
we're doing when it comes to Bangladesh
uh the India Bangladesh border is manned
by what the BSF the BSF is not the
Indian military it's not the Indian army
it's a paramilitary force it's a police
force which wears army uniforms and they
have automatic rifles and things like
that BSF and the BSF I mean just look at
news reports how many BSF officers have
been arrested for uh facilitating
facilitating Bangladeshi uh illegal
immigration into India I mean you know
look at the media reports the past 20
years or so
terrible um then you have crpf in
Manipur then you have Assam rifles in
Manipur I'm not going to go into those
organizations I think the less we say
about them the better okay but the the
consequence of all of the this this
corruption alleged corruption is that
more than 100 million Bangladeshi may be
in India right now and they are leeching
off India's resources and competing with
indians for resources and territory and
all that it's a
disaster they are in every major city
you can see them all over the place they
no longer even try to hide their
identities that speak in Bangladeshi
accented Bangla language and so on and I
wonder what the government of India is
doing when it comes to Illegal
immigration it's not a state issue it's
a central issue so what is the central
government doing and I've played the
video one of the videos of Mr Modi
promising in 2014 that the moment he
becomes prime minister Bangladesh will
be deported well how many have been
deported I think you think it's illegit
not not a legitimate question to
ask um so yeah I would say that Mr Modi
whatever he has done or not done the
past 11 years 10 and a half years after
becoming prime minister I think he has a
golden opportunity opportunity now Mr
Trump is going after the illegal
immigrants who are currently in the US
is going to deport them all all so if at
the same time India deports the illegal
Bangladeshi and cookies and ringas who
are all over the country I don't think
the US can complain because they they're
doing the same thing at the same time I
think this is the golden opportunity the
one opportunity that Mr Modi will ever
get to deport the
illegals I think he should take it let's
hope he takes it I don't I don't know
why he hasn't done it this far but I
hope that he takes the opportunity this
time vikam Ador says there was a report
which says that gur patwan sing panun
the khalistani terrorist the US citizen
khalistani terrorist was present in one
of Trump's inauguration events and uh he
was saying khalistan zindabad meters
away from Trump how come the US Secret
Service wasn't aware of this and they
are openly inviting a radicalist no
terrorist to such an important event how
should India deal with this and should
PM Modi leverage his b e omy with Trump
with President Trump to put pressure on
the
khalistanis so it is now clear that
panun was present at the inauguration
event or one of the events where Trump
was and he was in the same room As Trump
gur patan sing panu a US citizen who is
a terrorist who is a khalistani and he
was saying khalistan zindabad when
everyone was saying USA
USA so was the US Secret
Service not aware of this
do you think the US secret service is
not aware of anything they know
everything that's going
on they invited panon to the event why
did they do do that to send a message to
India that nothing's going to
change after Trump becomes president
nothing's going to change they're going
to keep on supporting khalistani
terrorism and separatism in India so the
US funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism in India against IND for
decades Pakistan was bleeding India
through terrorism for decades right from
the 1970s ' 80s '90s and 2000s until the
2000 at least even now it's going on now
you may perhaps say that the US is no
longer funding and financing it but the
1970s 80s 90s Etc 2000s the Americans
were funding in financing Pakistani
terrorism whether it was in Jammu and
Kashmir whether it was in in Punjab the
khalistan issue all that the Americans
were behind it Pakistan was their proxy
all right
so that's been America's long-standing
history and and policy towards India and
right now they see India as a potential
long-term competitor maybe in 20 30
years time India could potentially
become the next next form of China kind
of and they don't want that to happen so
they will do their best to hamper and
hinder India's growth economic growth
and the technological growth and and
whatever else India can do one of the
ways to do it is to uh forment
separatism and support anti-india
terrorists and separatists very easy
right so nothing is going to change
after Trump becomes president they will
continue to support khalistani terrorism
against India and khalistani separatists
and inviting panun to this event is a
great example of this so how should
India deal with this should PM Modi
leverage his friendship with Trump Mr
Modi has zero leverage on Mr
Trump okay you may be friends and they
may be on have cordal relations and Mr
uh Trump may say narandra is my good
friend and all
that it counts for nothing Mr Modi has
zero leverage on Trump how should India
deal with this India
should uh
swallow the pain and the hurt there's
nothing India can do about it of course
you can look there's really almost no
leverage that India has against the US
so it's just going to be the way it is
it's going to be status quo it's going
to be uh it's going to things will
continue the way they are they were
under the Biden regime not much will
change when it comes to these
issues anant Pai and uh Hedgehog's
dilemma I have this question Dr J
Shanker was seated India's foreign
minister Dr J Shanker was seated in the
FR first first row during President
Trump's inauguration while while other
foreign ministers were seated in the
third or fourth rle does this gesture
show show India's importance for the US
in the coming four years the Indian
foreign minister was given a front row
seat at the Trump inauguration does this
send a message to that the new Trump
government will be more friendly towards
India you know the Americans have known
for a very long time that Indians are
very big on
status if and and very the Indians are
very um receptive to flat
you see a few good words about India to
the Indians and they'll be all flattered
and they'll be all dancing around
dancing in the aisles and if you give
them some
special status then Indians will be like
overjoyed and they will do whatever you
want them to
do okay the Americans have known this
for a very long time look at old CIA
Declassified documents from the 1950s
and 60s and all that they've known it
about Indians for a very long
time um now it's possible that they
current Indian government is a more
hard-nosed Indian government more
realistic government that is not that
receptive to flatter in it doesn't make
much of a difference it's possible it's
possible that Dr J Shankar is is
obviously is one of the most experienced
foreign ministers and diplomats in the
world and he this will not really work
on him so what's the deal so why did
they give Dr J Shankar a front row seat
during uh Trump's
inauguration clearly there is some kind
of special uh status that they they
assign to India right the Trump
Administration what is the special uh
status that they have given to India I
think they they see India as the number
one nation they want to turn into an
American
wasal okay the Americans are going to
insist that India becomes a us vasal a
vasal a puppet a client state
so Indians who become American citizens
will find it very hard to to rise in
politics Vic is a great example okay the
H1B thing that's going on and there's a
huge backlash against Indians getting
H1B visas others can get it but Indians
if they get it it's it's bad so that's
going to be the situation in in the US
the the way Indians are regarded in the
US but they will want India to become a
US H I think that's why Dr J Shankar was
given a front row seat that we're going
to single you out for the special
treatment you will be our next big vasal
and we're going to use you against China
and whatnot but maybe maybe we will give
you some privileges you know if you're a
good boy good little boy then we'll
we'll let you exist we will not
interfere too much in your intern
Affairs maybe we'll ask Pakistan to back
off a little bit maybe we'll ask East
Pakistan Bangladesh to to you know tone
it down and maybe we will kind of put a
hold on Project K cookie land for Christ
but you become our wasal and then we
will um you know use you leverage you in
various ways against China I think
that's why Dr J Shankar got a front
roses it's not like India is some great
special Nation India is one of the few
thus far Sovereign nations in the world
one of the four Sovereign Nations but
let's see how long that lasts that's how
it works in an imperial system you know
and maybe it's a it's a good thing if
you if you become a us for all maybe
maybe so I I don't think the US
government the Trump government is going
to be specially friendly towards India
of course if we bend over and we do
everything they tell us to do then
they're going to be special super
friendly to us you as long as you do
what they say the moment you try and say
no to them you're going to find out how
nasty the US can
be okay mlin and vikor have this
question you said that Trump might give
us an ultimatum to become an American
Vel if that happens now how will we deal
with it are we capable of fighting them
if India becomes a wasal what will that
look like India is one of the rare
countries to have cordial ties with
Western Nations and Eastern Nations like
Russia part of the quad part of The
braks Cordial ties with both Iran and
Israel how long are we going to walk on
the tight rope trying to balance
relations in this polarized world and
will there come a time when we will have
to choose SIDS trusting the US is not
viable in the long run because they will
do anything everything to stop our rise
so it's better to have relations with
bricks Nations what are your views on
this Trump has already said that he's
going to smash brecks kind of you know
that sort of thing he's already said
very strong things about bricks that
bricks is a threat and Bricks needs to
whatever behave itself and so on so
bricks is going to be on his radar okay
he's going to go after bricks for sure
now um yeah it's a polarized world and
we have cordial ties which means
friendly ties and polite relations with
everybody with the East with the West
with the Americans with the EU nations
with NATO nations with Russia with Iran
with Israel with the Palestinians we are
friends of everyone
right
um how long is it to continue this
way I think it won't last for too long
now I think like mclan says Trump will
most likely very soon give India an
ultimatum you got to pick a side and if
you don't pick our side if you're not
with us you're going to be against us
that's what Trump will say to India how
should India deal with this well
straightforward you become a US wasal
you do what they say so which means that
you can no longer import arms from
Russia you have to uh buy American
weapon systems the biggest and the best
weapon system in the world okay we have
the best weapon systems you're going to
buy those from us that's what Trump will
say so we can no longer buy things from
the Russians we have to depend on the
Americans for jet engines and all that
and maybe we can um maybe we will have
to give overflight you know facilities
to American US Air Force aircraft maybe
give an air a military base or two to
the Americans somewhere on India's
peripheral territory you know those
things may happen I don't think it's
going to be uh
I think it's going to be hard for India
to remain completely um uh multi-
aligned or for India to to maintain its
strategic uh autonomy so-called
strategic
autonomy I think Trump is going to be
very clear very soon you got to pick a
side and if you're not with us you're
against us and we're going to do
everything to hurt you in that case I
think that's what's going to happen soon
and India is not strong enough to be
able to resist the US India is no match
to the US the Americans can destroy
India's economy in a week's time if they
want to you know so if they give us an
ultimatum there will be no choice for
India but to accept which means that
India Russia TI ties can be said can say
you can say goodbye to those and um
yeah that's what could happen I hope I
am wrong but that's how I see Donald
Trump's coming to power what it
signifies for India I hope I am wrong
but uh but but it may not be all bad to
be a us assal you can be an also run
kind of civilization for the next 100
years and maybe someday when the chance
comes we'll have someday hopefully a
good leader who can turn India into a
great nation and civilization in the
future right now we have no such leader
so that's where we
are PR Paul says if a republican
lawmaker resolution to amend the
Constitution and allow Donald Trump to
seek a third term comes to fruition what
could be the geopolitical implication
for us hegemony how would this impact
Global relations and power dynamics
especially with Rising Global challenges
could this shift in US leadership
potentially alter the direction of
international policies and the balance
of influence around the
world um yeah so I I heard the news
somewhere that uh some a republican
lawmaker or somebody um wants to amend
the Constitution and ow American
Presidents to have three terms in
office I don't think that's going to
happen first of all because of
constitutionality and legality and what
not the Supreme Court of the US probably
won't allow that okay and even if let's
say this happens because it's happened
in the past long long
ago let's say even if uh the
Constitution is amended and this is
allowed look Donald Trump has just
become the president right he's what 78
years old let's let's find out how old
he is let's go to Google our friend
Google how old is Donald
Trump um let's Google that Donald Trump
age okay he's 78 years old right now
okay so he's 78 now and in four years
time Donald Trump will be
82 you think it makes sense for a
nation to have an 82y old president
which means that once he is done with
his third term he'll be
86 now we've already seen the kind of
leadership that so-called leadership
that Biden provided to the US at that
advanced age I don't think Donald Trump
himself would want to become president a
third time I I could be completely wrong
because he's a well he's one of a kind
so who
knows I think he's going to do
everything in his power to completely
reshape the world and the US the next
four years
and turn turn The World from being under
the so-called rules based world order to
be to being under the under an outright
imperial
system and it's going to turn the us
into the greatest and biggest and
baddest empire ever that's what I think
he's going to do and I think four years
is enough for him to do that in four
years the us could become a space
fairing power a multiplanetary power
they could have Mars territory on Mars
that they call the their Road and nobody
else can do that and they could be and
by the time um open AI Etc may have
achieved artificial super intelligence I
think AGI must have already happened
artificial general intelligence I think
by the time they will achieve artificial
super intelligence which makes
them you know which which gives them
superpowers essentially hyper Powers
possibly the next four years could be
enough for that and in that case I don't
think he will need a third
term uh so I think it's unlikely but
let's see let's let's wait and see how
it goes let's wait and
watch uh PR Paul says why did Dr foui
need a pardon and what does it say about
the power of a US president to Pardon
anyone in the final moments of their
office does this undermine the Integrity
of the office when pardons are issued to
family members and controversial figures
at the 11th the 11th hour so it's not
like um the US president can only pardon
somebody when they're about to uh Dem
office it's not like that uh they can
pardon somebody a person anytime during
the tenor's president on the first day
on during the second year or whenever
okay it's not like it has to be at the
last moment but Biden or whoever is
controlling Biden has pardoned a whole
bunch of people I think Biden has given
more presidential pardons than anybody
else in the history of the US uh one of
these was to his son Hunter Biden his
son was well what can I say I mean the
less we say about Hunter Biden the
better an absolute criminal right with
who done the worst kind of
things but he's been pardoned and uh
various family members of Biden have
been pardoned and Dr fouchi has been
pardoned which makes us makes us wonder
what did what crimes did foui commit
that he he needed to be pardoned by the
US president by Biden foui obviously is
the guy who was the the architect
allegedly of the of the US response to
the Corona virus uh
pandemic some allege that he was the
architect of the P pandemic itself or
somebody that sort of things so we don't
know but clearly he must have done
things that were terrible right that's
why Biden needed to Pardon him and maybe
he needed to do that to cover things up
for himself as well perhaps or or the or
his
administration um it's just the way it
is okay does it under the Integrity of
the you of the office of the US
president I don't think so it's always
been this way but this time it's been um
used to an extent that's that's never
happened before right it doesn't
undermine the the office of the US
president uh it obviously is a bad look
when you're pardoning your family
members who clearly have been um
involved in various crimes and all it's
a bad look but
uh um it's it's just the way it is look
the US is the most powerful Nation it's
an Empire and things such as these
happen in an Empire the emperor can do
things which prime ministers cannot do
for
example duner sing Johan and PR Paul
what do you think about the Nazi Salute
by Elon Musk Elon musk's Nazi salute at
the inauguration has drawn attention
what does it say about his public
Persona and how could it affect his
influence in Tech and politics so I'm
not going to do what it did okay uh the
salute that he did Elon Musk says that
he put his hand on his heart and then he
said that I give out this love to the
people or that sort of thing that's the
kind of uh justification or explanation
Elon Musk has given
um well this salute it's not originally
a Nazi salute okay it was used by the
Nazis but
2,000 years ago it was a Roman salute
the Romans had the same salute I mean if
you watch Recreations I mean historical
Recreations of Roman times if you watch
various movies and series that have they
have about Rome you will find the same
salute being uh being given by Roman
soldiers legionaries and all
so but of course these days um It's
associated with the Nazis so it's it's
it's not seen as good form to do that
but ilon mus did that and then his
support reporters on Twitter have put
out various other clips of other world
leaders doing Sim similar kind of
gestures you know gestures that are
similar to that
um that's that's what's transpired in
the past couple of days on social media
what do I think about this I think that
Elon Musk knows that nobody can touch
him today he has the full support just
like Trump does of the American
establishment he may actually have more
of the US establishment or deep State
support than Trump possibly because he
is he is at the the he's their spearhead
when it comes to uh solar sister
colonization solar solar system
colonization um the starlink network
that essentially s is a surveillance
network of the entire world and so much
more uh so I think Elon Musk knows
nobody can touch him no matter what he
does he will have the support of the
establishment which U allows him to do
things that most people can't do so it
will not affect
his influence or power in
technology or in politics right now he's
like number two in the US after Trump uh
the vice president JD van doesn't have
anything like the kind of power Elon
Musk does so Elon Musk has been very
smart he has used his wealth to to uh
invest in critical Technologies like
space
exploration like uh satellites the
starlink constellation he got thousands
of those satellites which which gives
them tremendous power and uh batteries
electric vehicles batteries you know
those Hamas pagers if a if if a battery
can explode imagine what a gigantic car
battery can do so there is that and the
booring company and those tunnels and
all that that he constructing all across
the US it gives him tremendous power so
and he is the the backing of the
establishment so he's Untouchable
essentially nothing can happen to him
he's going to be fine so he can do
whatever he wants including what looks
like a Nazi
salute the feminist Slayer says will the
development of AI artificial
intelligence to its full extent cause
humans to lose their intelligence and
become slaves to the oligarchs I observe
that many depressed individuals are are
relying on AI chatbots and AI
girlfriends to feel free avoiding
forming friendships with real people
what's the ultimate agenda behind this
advancement in artificial intelligence
you know a lot of people believe that AI
is a commodity that will allow American
companies to become rich okay so you
have chap GPT open AI that is selling
multi- tired subscriptions the lowest
Tire I believe is $20 a month in which
you get a certain kind of capability
that at your disposal of the AI and then
the recently they've come up with a new
higher Tire which is about $200 a month
in which you get like much more powerful
access to a much more powerful AI system
much more powerful version of their Ai
and so a lot of people think that it's
about making these companies Rich
they're going to get really rich by
because all the the are the ones who
have this this uh technology and the
whole world wants to use it but it's not
just about the
money okay AI is not just about the
money it's actually about
power so you have a EU politicians like
Kier starmer who are saying that uh we
should not get left behind we should
also have a slice of the pie we should
also make some money then you have
what's her name Ula fer Lan the EU
president who is saying some things like
that similar things Biden said some such
similar things um open AI uh what's his
name whoever the guy is um Sam Alman
they're all saying that it's all about
the money but actually it's not about
money it's about power how is it about
power and it's not about see which are
the main uh companies that have Top
Class AI systems open AI obviously is
one um then you have perplexity that
kind of is a wrapper on top of other AIS
so that's not really that powerful so
you have open AI you have Gro you have
clothe and the Chinese have come with
deep seek and so on so they got you got
three or four of these companies that
have Top Class AI
systems and uh what they have disclosed
to the world the best AI system they
have disclosed to the world the world is
obviously not the best that they have
the best that they have is going to be
secret so it's quite so it is said that
we are about three to five years from
AGI artificial general intelligence what
is Agi AGI is is an AI system that is as
intelligent as a reasonably intelligent
human being and can do everything a
reasonably intelligent human being can
do it's like being the equ equivalent of
a human with about 130 IQ 130 is
supposed to be is said to be good like
really intelligent genius level IQ is
150 130 is like very very good IQ so an
a system with that sort of IQ can do
everything a human with that sort of IQ
can do and that's what we call AGI
artificial general intelligence now an
AGI system can improve itself
iteratively and soon become within a few
years an ASI system artificial super
intelligence an ASI system is like a
human being with IQ 300 or 500 which
means no such human exists or could
exist it's a superum system and when you
have an ASI system with IQ about 500 it
can uh develop transformative
Technologies technologies that look like
that seem like magic to us time travel
and and wormholes and whatnot you know
that sort of thing so if once you have
an ASI system you are the master of the
universe and then you can ensure that
nobody else can catch up with you so
that's all about power it's not about
money no one cares about money when you
when you're talking about capacity of
that kind of magnitude right um so it's
about power ultimately and who will hold
that power is the question let's say
open AI develops an ASI system will Sam
Alman be the emperor of the universe he
want it's the US government which will
be the emperor of the universe because
they control s man and on all the assets
that open AI owns on us soil or wherever
because they control most of the world
world so at the end of the day it's the
US government that's going to end up
becoming the hyperpower so AI is not
about money it's about power it's about
it's nothing except power and the
development of AI to its full extent
will cause one entity the US government
most likely to become the dominant
entity for the foreseeable future let's
let's say a thousand
years and the rest of humanity will
essentially do the bidding of the US
government once this happens will we
become slaves if they are nice enough
they we will they will not make us
slaves but we will kind of continue to
exist in some kind
of uh in whatever shape or form they
want humans to
exist so you know that's that's just the
direction in which the world is going
right now I wish I could sugarcoat it
but that's the deal it's about making
whoever owns the ASI system so that's
why everybody is is is is is trying
their best to develop AI right throwing
in IM immense insane amounts of money
into uh developing AI infrastructure
like Stargate for example which we'll
discuss shortly it's all about power
it's nothing to do with money it's all
about power money is no money is not a
is not a constraint over here it's about
power it's about becoming the ultimate
power in the known universe that's what
the race for AI is like so the US is
involved a number of us companies are
involved and the Americans have brought
them together and Stargate and then you
have China which is trying something the
Russians are not really involved you
know in the running as far as we know as
we know and India is still wondering
should we become an AI power should we
um invest in our own AI models or should
we just use American models to to to
create Commodities and and and solutions
to various problems that's what Nandan
Dei wants us to do um yeah so India is
not participating in this race only the
Americans and the Chinese
are okay ramal lakmi and PR Paul ramal
lakmi says the Chinese open-sourced deep
seek models are almost beating the open
a ow models and their computation was a
fraction of theirs India should also
develop and have India's own models and
compete what do I think PR Paul says
with a small Chinese lab like deep seek
creating a reasoning llm large language
model comparable to chat gpd's final
model so far so far for just $5.5
million equivalent to the uh annual
salary of meta's AI leaders and
achieving this as a side project what
does this say about the Chinese
engineering mindset and approach to
Innovation does this challenge the
Western narrative that massive budgets
and high-end infrastructure are
essential for AI breakthroughs and could
it reshape the global AI race toward
cost efficient impactful solution
so the Chinese uh firm deep seek I think
it's called or maybe the product is
called Deep seek so the Chinese have
developed this uh well a Chinese firm
has developed this AI system called Deep
seek so this is a Chinese quantitative
trading firm okay quantitative trading
trading is algorithmic trading uh you
make split-second decisions you know
millisecond microsc decisions on the
stock market and you are not day trading
you're not hour trading you're not
second trading you are nanc trading
essentially
every nanc counts in
this so they had invested in a
tremendous amount of GPU architecture
okay and
uh to to run this quantitative trading
system and they hired over the years the
best possible researchers researchers
from mathematics and physics backgrounds
mainly and uh very young guys you know
22 23 24 is the median age average age
that's what this firm did and uh the
Chinese government gave them their full
backing okay and as a side project they
created this uh this deep seek large
language model because they had this
tremendous amount of GPU architecture
that they had already acquired for their
quantitative trading trading business
and some of it was not being utilized so
let's maximize the gpus by running by
developing this large language model on
that so that was the deal so as a side
project they developed deep seek now
they say that it cost them about 5.5
million um no I'm not very sure about
that because they would have needed
Nvidia gpus for that and Trump and Biden
have essentially banned Nvidia from
selling top of the line gpus to China
but China would have acquired these gpus
from other places like from other
countries in Asia like Taiwan for
example or wherever so they can't really
disclose that they we have acquired
Nvidia top ofth line gpus from so and so
country circumventing us sanctions and
all that now these gpus they cost a lot
of money but obviously when you give the
figure of 5.5 million you are not
including that that amount that money
that you spend on the Nvidia gpus in
that so I'm sure it would have cost more
than 5.5 million significantly more
let's say 50 million or 100 million even
that's not a tremendous am amount of
money money when it comes to developing
a large language model which supposedly
outperforms chat gpt's 01 a model in in
a lot of in a lot of ways
right um so it's possible it's possible
all you need is is let's say 10 20 high
quality researchers you know uh
programmers and you you sequester them
in in a in a in a building for six
months you give them as much money as
they need and all the hardware they need
and they're going to do it so the
Chinese have demonstrated that you don't
need a lot of money and a lot of
resources to develop a worldclass large
language
model uh so let's say it costs 50
million including the Nvidia hardware
gpus and all that why isn't somebody in
India doing it because nobody in India
seems to have the ambition we have
people like Nandan Nani who said that
India should not develop its own models
India should simply use American models
and build on top of that
such people uh I I I don't know what to
say about such people people with no
ambition they they have personal
ambition for their companies and their
business to make as much money as
possible but they don't care about
India's position in the
world um so yeah it what what uh what
deeps has achieved it does tell you that
you don't you don't need tremendous
amounts of money billions and billions
of of dollars massive budgets and
tremendous mend infrastructure uh to
become a world leader in AI it it tells
us that India can still achieve
something if if a private company or the
Indian government for example wants this
to happen let's say the private
companies are not interested because
they have no ambition let's say okay
they only seek uh profits for themselves
they don't care about India's
geopolitical uh position in the world
why can't the Indian government hire
let's say 20 or 50
college graduates or university
graduates the average age should be 22
23 24 find the best of the lot 50 of
them maximum or 20 or 30 of them you
give them a salary of one CR a month you
have 20 that's just 20 CR a month which
is nothing which is peenuts for the
government of India it's it's it's not
even peenuts for the government of India
the government of India has so much
money you cannot imagine how much money
the government has so hire 25 people
let's say the best of the lot give each
of them one CR a month so that they are
happy and they will never complain
that's simply 25 crores a month give
them all the gpus and everything they
need let's say it costs you 20 or 30 or
$50 million which is again nothing for
India nothing for the government of
India you give them everything they need
you put them in a in a in a five star
facility okay air condition facility you
give them all all the food all the
whatever they need okay you give them
six months one year they're going to do
it that's all you need my question is
does the government of India have this
ambition forget about the private
companies private firms all the
billionaires they don't
care why can't the government of India
do this I simply don't understand I
can't comprehend the mindset of the
government of India uh maybe they've
just accepted that that Donald Trump is
going to ask us to become a us wasal and
we're going to accept and that's the
best way forward for India going
forwards forward we should not compete
with the Americans otherwise they'll
destroy us maybe that's the reasoning
maybe that sound log maybe that's not I
don't know I would like to see India
show some
fight uh but at the end of the day the
it's not in our hands right it's
not ramal lakmi Pan gonar and sidara the
question is about Stargate the Stargate
project of the US valued at $500 billion
dollar aims to build data centers and
become a Powerhouse of AI for the next
four in the next four years do you think
it's even possible four years we
know we know this is all done for
computer and training more data Etc what
are your thoughts uh good God Stargate
project is announced with a funding of
$500 billion do the crazy thing is that
building for Stargate the building of
this project has has already started
when will they achieve AGI artificial
general intelligence Sid Bara says what
are your thoughts on projects Target I
mean who can even compete against 500
million billion dollars Imperial AI
Imperial era of AI is upon us scary
times
ahead okay Stargate a lot of um concern
if you are not in the US and uh the the
money that is being the amount of money
that has been announced is is
mindboggling $500 billion half a
trillion and so on right what's India's
defense budget annually about 80 billion
US dollar penuts compared to what they
what they're throwing at Stargate right
so what is this Stargate AI project
which has been announced like what the
day that Trump was inaugurated right
it's it's it's an artificial
intelligence AI initiative announced on
the day that Trump was inaugurated
January 21st this year and they have
said that about $500 billion do is going
to be invested in AI infrastructure
across the US the next four years which
is by 2029 which will be the AI
equivalent of the Manhattan Project
which is the project that developed the
nuclear bomb in the US now the question
is who are the main participants in this
project the US government is not a main
participant or a key participant in the
project the founding Partners who are
they first of all there's open AI okay
Sam alman's company then there's
something called Soft bank which comes
out of Japan and there's Oracle which is
an American company and then you have um
a firm called mgx which is from Abu
Dhabi so the leadership of this target
project uh the leader essentially the
chairman is going to be masayoshi son
who's the CEO of soft Bank okay uh he's
a tremendously rich person from
Japan so uh the leadership the chairman
is going to be masayoshi son from Japan
uh the operational aspects of the
Stargate project are going to be
overseen by open AI That's Sam Altman's
company and the financial operations
will be managed by Soft bank which is
again Masa
Yoshis so the initial investment that's
been announced is 100 billion apparently
it's already been invested invested and
over the next four years it's going to
be ramped up scaled up to 500 billion
and what you're going to see is the
construction you're going to see
construction of multiple data centers
across the US okay lots of lots of
machines computers which will be data
centers racks of machines and the first
such facilities is already under
construction somewhere in Texas and
initially there's going to be 10 data
centers and potentially you're going to
have more locations maybe 20 more
locations or that sort of thing the
objective of the project is to create
the best our AI infrastructure in the
world in the US okay it's going to
generate jobs 100,000 or so us us jobs
it's going to boost the US economy and
maintain us leadership in a technology
but it's going to provide open AI all
the infrastructure it needs to overcome
any potential future bottlenecks in data
or computing power so they have this
this thing going on with Microsoft this
tgof war going on between um between Sam
Alman and SAA nadela about the is aure
aure uh computing power and all that so
this project will ensure that openi does
not face any future potential
bottlenecks either when it comes to
computing power or or the amount of data
it wants to store and and work on okay
and obviously you're going to have the
best uh AI server chips gpus best data
center uh technology you may have
nuclear power being involved in this to
meet very high power demands because all
this would take tremendous amounts of
power right and obviously for this you
need collaboration with the tech giants
like
Nvidia for
Hardware uh for the hardware
requirements and arm Holdings for
software Solutions
so all of that now there's been a
question about whe whether there's
enough
funding um so I'm sure the funding will
be there and the funding is not being
put forth by the US government the US
government is not part of this at all
well except as an overseer from above so
the funding is going to be put for put
put forth by the private companies and
and uh investors okay um so that's how
it's going to be
so so it it so this project it brings
together
competitors to create a shared AI
infrastructure so in the US you have
competitors right you have open air
which is jousting with Microsoft and
there is this thing there Nvidia there's
Oracle there's arm Holdings there is
soft Bank many of these are competitors
especially open a and Microsoft but they
have been brought together in a single
project who can do it somebody bigger
and stronger and more powerful can do it
which only means the US
government okay
um
so open Ai and Microsoft are direct
competitors but they
will they will work together in this and
Oracle and Microsoft are also
competitors when it comes to cloud
services but they will all work together
and at the end of the day it's about
achieving and ensuring and consolidating
US hegemony when it comes to artificial
intelligence so that is the Stargate
project it's it is kind of scary it is
the final push for complete world
domination essentially $500 billion you
can I cannot even imagine the things
that you can achieve with that can
Nations like China compete with the US
India I don't even know if they even
bothered to compete but can China
compete with what the Americans are
doing even the Chinese I'm sure can put
forth that sort of money $500 billion
I'm sure the government of China is
capable of doing that but yeah the ball
is I don't know it's in the corner of
the chines and the whoever else wants to
compete because the Americans have made
it very clear with this project that
they are
100% serious about being the world
Hederman for the next 1,000 years by
doing
this okay Lost Child Vikram geopolitical
and Shah Nisar have questions about
scramjet engines and the scramjet test
that was done recently by
India so India successfully tested a
scramjet engine for the first time why
don't we use scramjet engines in jet in
fighter planes ddu has successfully
conducted a ground test of a scramjet
engine which can be used in Mac 5
Hypersonic missiles what are my views on
this and what are my thoughts on the Dio
conducting a key test in scramjet
technology development and what is a
scramjet engine and Shan has been
listening to me for three years thank
you so much I really appreciate that
okay so let's begin uh with what is a a
scramjet engine right a scramjet engine
is
U so there are various kinds of
propulsion Technologies
okay um when it comes to
missiles you you have solids solid fuel
missiles liquid fuel missiles which uses
cryogenic technology then you have scram
Jets now scram jets are usually are used
only for cruise
missiles not for rockets that are
supposed to go outside of the atmosphere
and place things into orbit I'll tell
you why
so because of that you can't even use
scramjets for ballistic missiles unless
you're using them as as one of the first
stages or something because ballistic
missiles they exit the atmosphere do a
parabolic trajectory and then reenter
the atmosphere so scramjets cannot be
used for ballistic missiles unless it's
in the first or second stage or
something and they can't be used for you
know the pslv gslv uh Starship kind of
rockets you can't so a scramjet is a
super combusting Ramjet engine a Ramjet
engine is uh an engine that can
accelerate uh your vehicle to Mac 2 to
Mac 5 Mac one is one times the speed of
sound Mac 2 is twice the speed of sound
Mac 5 is five times the speed of sound
okay so Ramjet
engines they work efficiently at
supersonic speeds between Mac 1 to Mac
3 and they can operate up to Mac 5 also
but uh they become inefficient around
Mac 5 and higher than that because of
various uh because of various technical
reasons so a Ramjet engine typically
works best around Mac 2 Mac 3 the
brahmos missile has a Ramjet engine okay
which is the second stage of the of the
brahmos the first stage is a
conventional solid state rocket which
accelerates the the missile to Beyond
Mac 1 and then the Ramjet takes over and
then it takes the missile to Mac 2 or
whever it
is so that's what a ram jet is is and a
scramjet is something that is a super
combusting Ramjet super combusting uh
supersonic Ramjet so it for scramjet
needs the air inflow into the into the
engine to be at supersonic speeds and
then it will accelerate the missile or
the vehicle to Hypersonic speeds which
is in excess of Mac 5 Mac 6 okay U so
what is supersonic speed it is about Mac
1 to Mac 5 okay one time one times the
speed of sound to five times the speed
of sound Hypersonic speeds are Mac 5 to
Mac 10 or maybe yeah Mac Mac 5 to Mac
Mac 10 then you have high HP high
Hypersonic speeds which are Mac 10 to
Mac
25 thereabouts and then you have
re-entry speeds which is Mac 25 or
higher which which is typically
ballistic missiles and meteorites and
all that Mac 25 or higher so the
Russian C missile has a maximum speed of
about Mac 9 or Mac 10 it has a ram a a
scramjet
engine so scramjets like I said are
designed to they work most efficiently
at at at Hypersonic speeds and ramjets
work best at Super Sonic
speeds and these engines they use so
when you have an engine you have a fuel
and you have an
oxidizer the fuel could be whatever it
could be aviation fuel which is kerosene
it could be a cryogenically liquified
gases like hydrogen or
methane and so on and your oxid oxidizer
is typically oxygen or hydrogen peroxide
or whatever okay so in a scramjet and a
Ramjet the oxidizer is the oxygen of the
atmosphere so these engines they only
the only fuel they they they uh have is
is either uh whatever um liquefied
hydrogen or methane or maybe some other
form of fuel and the oxidizer is always
taken from the atmosphere itself okay
now India has successfully tested about
a week or so ago or recently a scram
engine is that the first time India has
successfully tested a scram engine it's
not so let us go to
isro's website
right and take a look at
this this is an article from 2006
January 10 2006 ISRO achieves
breakthrough in supersonic combustion
technology okay uh the Vikram Sarai
Center of ISRO at tyu anantapuram in
January 2006 successfully carried out
the design development characterization
in realization of a scramjet through a
series of ground tests a stable
supersonic combustion was demonstrated
for nearly second 7 seconds with a Mac
inl Inlet Mac number of six Mac six six
times the speed of sound this was
okay now then you have this other piece
of news which
is from where is it where is it where is
it
um where's the date
bro one second I think it's 2016 yeah
so there was a successful flight testing
of a scramjet by ISRO on August 28
2016 so as you can see ISRO and whoever
in the government of India has been
developing a scramjet engine and the
first news that we have is from 2006
where you had a a ground test then you
had a flight test in 2016 and now in
2025 we have carried out another ground
test at looks like uh where is the
question yeah ground test
so as you can see the development is
slow and uh India becomes one of the one
of the few nations with this technology
but we need to put that engine on an
actual aircraft or missile and
demonstrate that it works fine and then
induct it into the Armed Forces that's
what we need to do uh it's been more
than 20 years we we've been developing
this now what I'm saying is not
criticism of the engineers who are
working on this this is a very difficult
technology to
master you know when
your air
intake has supersonic
speeds it's it's very hard to to sustain
combustion in that case it's like trying
to keep a candle lit during a
hurricane during a cyclone it's almost
impossible but you got to master this
technology so it takes time to do this
but we have been doing this for quite
some time and I think now it's time for
us to
uh finally deploy this technology
hopefully uh of course you have to give
some criticism because development of
technology in India takes a very long
time longer than it typically should and
it's not the fault of the engineers and
scientists it's typically because of the
bureaucracy and the and the slow speed
at which your your funding is allocated
and all that so A lot has to do with the
bureaucracy and a lot has to do with the
political leadership which maybe don't
see these Technologies as something that
is priority over freeb and all that I
don't know I'm just saying so I think
it's a great thing that we have
conducted this test I think we need to
take it to its logical conclusion and
deploy this technology
operationally uh now the first question
by Lost Child over here is why don't we
use cram jet engines in jet planes so
let's say you have a fighter plane like
the thees which can go above Mac one
which is a supersonic fighter plane
let's say you put a
scramjet uh engine in a on a tagious
fighter plane what's going to happen
first of all you will have to First Take
This the aircraft
Supersonic in order to be able to ignite
the scramjet so how do you make the
aircraft go Super Sonic in the first
place you will need some other form of
propostion
first okay so the scramjet engine you
cannot start it when the plane is
stationary on the ground you can't even
start it when the plane is flying get
500 km/ hour it has to go beyond Mac 1
only then can you ignite the scramjet
engine that's the first thing okay
secondly let's say you put a rocket
booster on the Tas and you put two
scramjet engines on the Tes or one let's
say and then you use the rocket booster
for the initial Mac 1 plus boost and
then you ignite the scram jet okay let's
say then the scramjet will ignite it's
going to go
Hypersonic it's going to go beyond Mark
can this airframe of the Tes fighter
plane or the Suk 30 or sukko 57 or the
jaguar or the Rafal whichever fighter
plane you can imagine can the air
airframe of that fighter plane withstand
a Mac 5 plus flight or Mac 6 Plus FL
flight because at that speed the air
resistance and the friction with the
molecules of the atmosphere is going to
cause the the air frame to have a
temperature of hundreds of degrees
Centigrade hundreds of degrees
Centigrade can the airframe withstand
that can the glass canopy of the cockpit
withstand the temperature it's going to
start glowing red you need special
materials for that like uh for example
the materials that were used in the
SR sr81 was it uh Blackbird what was it
called
sr81 black black
bird SR71 Black Bird yes R 71 black
world if you want to see what I'm
talking about uh let me put that on the
screen so the Americans had a Hypersonic
Hypersonic plane um the locked SR71
Blackbird and this aircraft was coed
with a special material and uh it had
all kinds of uh measures taken that
ensure that it its uh its structure not
did not combust or burn up because of
the extreme heat and pressure of the
atmosphere at that at those speeds
so a typical normal fighter plane like
the Tas or the soo 57 or the soo 30 or
Soo 35 or Rafal or whatever can't
withstand those speeds it can't they're
not designed to withstand those speeds
you need a whole different kind of
design and shape of the aircraft to be
able to withstand Hypersonic speeds it's
going to be shaped like a like a rocket
essentially right uh there is that and
secondly if you have a fighter plane
that's Hypersonic it won't be able to
maneuver the way a standard fighter plan
can maneuver at Mac 1 or Mac 2 see you
have some fighter planes that are very
maneuver maneuverable like the mig21 was
the the legendary mig21 which is now
museum piece but we still operate it's
very
maneuverable the sukko fighter planes
because of thrust vectoring are very
maneuverable they can do the pugach of
Cobra and and such Maneuvers when you
have a Hypersonic plane you can't do all
that hyper maneuvering and you you
traveling so fast you can't even indulge
in dog fight
so you can't have Hypersonic uh engines
scram Jets on a fighter
plane you you simply can't because then
you then you can't maneuver at that
speed that maneuvering dog fighting all
that so you can use it for
reconnaissance planes or missiles the
best use for scramjets is on missiles so
if you want a Hypersonic brahos a ma n
Mark 9 Mark 10 brahos new version then
you would use a scram jet on it right
now we user Ramjet so that's the deal
and it's great that India has tested
this technology and developed shown that
we can use it and we are capable of
doing it but we need to take it to its
logical
conclusion test it in the air multiple
times and then deploy it build new
missiles or or whatever that uses that
that use this engine and deploy it
operationally that's what we need to
do Vikram geopolitical says the isi
chief was recently on a trip to
Bangladesh and has agreed on various
terms including sharing intelligence Etc
Bangladesh is also planning to buy 32
jf1 17s from Pakistan should India be
worried about this can Pakistan
Bangladesh and China together P put a
threat to Siliguri Corridor and
sovereignty of Northeast
India okay first of all let's understand
Who's involved which big Power is
involved in
this in 2022 Imran Khan was Ed from
power in West Pakistan right and uh who
I think it was shabas Sharif or whoever
came to power is who was put in in the
seat of prime minister and this was a
coup and this coup was orchestrated by
the Americans and after the out of Imran
Khan west Pakistan once again became a
us wasal a US puppet us vasal us client
State West Pakistan now shikina has been
oued last year from East Pakistan which
was Bangladesh and now you have a pro us
puppet
government in Bangladesh or east
Pakistan and the nominal head is
Muhammad eunus so both East and West
Pakistan are us
proxies are us
vasal now do you know what China is
China is the number two adversary of the
US after Russia you think two us vasal
will cooperate with the US
adversary doesn't make
sense doesn't make sense so I don't
think China is cooperating with Pakistan
and Bangladesh right now it's not
possible for them to do that because
both Pakistan and Bangladesh are us
vasal please understand the simple logic
I'm not saying that China is is a great
friend of indas China is an
adversary okay and right now there may
be some kind of rosmo some kind of Theon
some kind of tha in relations but India
will have to be very careful each step
of the way in dealing with
China uh so I don't see China Pakistan
and Bangladesh coming together to put a
threat to the Siliguri Corridor no the
the threat to the Siliguri Corridor
comes only from China Bangladesh is no
match for
India if the Bangladesh is try to make a
move on the Siliguri Corridor they we
can slice their country into five pieces
if we want the Indian military is
capable of doing that very easily uh if
the Bangladesh is acquire fighter plays
from Pakistan JF 17s or whatever it
could make things a little bit more
headache worthy for India but still we
can deal with Bangladesh so Bangladesh
is not a military threat to India of any
kind they are a nuisance for India
because of their status new new newly
minted status is a us
vasal um there is that now when it comes
to the Northeast the Far East of India
the Chinese wanted to break it off from
India they still may have forces over
there that are Chinese proxies so that's
a deal that's that's thing and
Bangladesh is is going to cause a lot of
trouble for India in this region in
tripura and wherever else they can so
yeah it's going to be a growing headache
for India you're gonna have more
infiltration you're gonna have more
terrorism more separatism and so
on uh so yeah it's it's a very
complicated situation in India's Far
East China is not really a friend okay
China has historically been an adversary
in this region they have funded and
financed various terrorist and
separatist organizations going back to
the 1950s and
1960s um in the Far East of India okay
um the Americans are right now involved
in this project K operation in in the
region to create an artificial Christian
cookie
Nation out of uh out of um parts of
Burma parts of mizoram and Manipur and
parts of Bangladesh possibly the
Americans may be in the process soon of
building a a military base out of St
Martin's Island which is in the region
so it's complicated and Bangladesh is
now very hostile towards India and you
are seeing all kinds of Trouble On the
Border and obviously we have had this
issue it is our mistake it's our fault
our failing that our border security
Force allegedly has been allegedly I'm
saying allegedly look at the media
reports on all that how many officers
have been jailed and court marshalled so
the BSF and other paramilitary forces
whoever else may or may not be involved
have allegedly been complicit in
bringing Bangladeshi infiltrators into
India in very large numbers so all kinds
of problems um the central government of
has had 10 years plus to deal with this
thing and nothing has been done thus far
so it's very is very very unfortunate
but yeah it's going to be an increasing
headache for India this whole situation
for
us okay um Elan Gran from a from Armenia
says Elan Gran from Armenia says the
aeran people call us Indians call us
Armenians Indians they think they're
insulting us but they don't understand
that not only are we not offended but we
have also received the opportunity to be
friends with one of the fastest growing
countries in the world
yes um if you see the chatter on on on
social media you will see Turkish people
and aeran people calling Armenians
Indians and they use this term Indians
as an insult towards the Armenians why
do they do this why do they call
Armenians
Indians right well the fact is that
there are historical ties between India
and Armenia going back more than 2,000
years going back maybe more than two and
a half thousand years
uh there is some some kind of connection
between India and Armenia I'm not sure
what it is uh we know that there were
there were some Hindu temples in Aria
2,000 years ago which were destroyed and
churches were built on top of them and
then those churches have recently been
destroyed and mosques have been built on
top of them by the AER Banis that sort
of thing so there have been very ancient
relations between India and Armenia um
there is some kind of genetic Affinity
also between India and Armenia uh I hope
in the future geneticists can uncover
what the Deep history is is but anyway
whatever that be U the Turks and the
aeran try to insult Armenians by calling
them Indians because Armenians are not
wh- skinned people they have slightly
light brown skin or whatever and that's
why the Turks like to insult them by
calling them Indians um and India has
been supplying
Armenia uh with Weaponry weapon systems
Radars arms ammunition missiles Rockets
all that in its um struggle to stay
independent and and continue to exist as
a nation because the Turks the and the
aeran want to destroy Armenia right and
create this panan
Corridor and India is essentially the
only nation that's
helping Armenia and against Armenia you
have Nations like turkey aeran even
Israel so India and Israel are
adversaries in this conflict interesting
isn't it uh so one of the few friends
Armenia has is India and uh so yeah so
the Turks obviously because of that also
are they like to insult the think that
they can insult the Armenians by calling
them by calling them Indians but uh yeah
so it's unfortunate that Armenia is in
this situation and uh it's good that
India is supporting Armenia and I think
we should continue the support to
Armenia Armenia is one of the
oldest uh cultures in the world at least
2 and a half thousand years it has
existed it's probably the first
Christian nation in the world one of
probably the first nation that became
Christian I'll not go into that history
but yeah uh and Armenians have traded
with India for
centuries
um if you if
you go to places like Surat for
example you will find um a place called
I think it's called The Dutch Cemetery
or something where you have Armenian
graes also that go back about 4500
years and the Armenians did not come to
India to plunder India unlike the Dutch
and the in the in the Portuguese and the
the English the Armenians were simply
Traders so good people so I think we
should be friends with Armenia we should
support the Armenians the the good
people of Armenia and uh let the Turks
think that they can insult you how do we
care okay Mr Carrot and Luffy saturo say
the JFK files are going to be
Declassified do you think they will
reveal anything and Trump declass IFI
the JFK files today do you think they
will re reveal the truth that the
CIA allegedly themselves killed John F
Kennedy what do I think is going to
happen do you people do my friends my
viewers do you remember several years
ago Prime Minister Modi Declassified the
subash Chandra BOS
files okay and a whole lot of documents
were made public did they reveal
anything about the big
mystery nothing right so the see so
Trump is going to I think he has
Declassified the JFK files it's going to
reveal nothing
whatsoever it will throw no new light on
the mystery of who killed John F Kennedy
okay it's gonna make no difference to
the world it'll bring it'll shed no new
light on who really was behind the
killing of John F Kennedy and I saw some
of those images you know scanned images
of some of the documents that were
Declassified a whole document with every
single line of text blacked out blacked
out so you can see the date and some
header and some footer and everything
else in between is blacked out do you
call that declassification really so
it's going to make no difference it's
going to shed no light on what really
happened and who really was behind the
assassination of John F Kennedy okay and
I'm not going to go into the
uh what shall we call speculation
conspiracy theories or whatever right
about who may have been behind this I I
obviously have my own hunch but I'm not
going to air that because there's no
evidence okay it's all speculation
without actual hard evidence to back it
up okay Amit what am viit God okay
whatever the name is the question is is
I am an Indian student currently
studying BC honors physics good job in
the
UK long time viewer of yours but asking
a question for the first time the reason
I'm studying here is simple lack of
meritocracy in India especially after
the 12th standard I completely
understand my friend I want to know your
opinion on Indian politicians choosing
to spend estimated 2 trillion rupees or
21 billion usar annually on
freebies do these idiots
really not see further than the upcoming
election forget planning for a century
ahead Ai and Quantum technology
something more than a decade away and
yet we are not spending anything there
that is why sometimes my Bloods blood
boils when most politicians and their
blind followers on both sides say that
we simply don't have the funds that is
in most simple terms simple terms buying
out the
votes so what you are speaking about
speaking about is the ground reality of
politics in India no matter which
political party you're from or no matter
who you are in
politics Your Existence and relevance in
politics depends is is solely dependent
on how many votes you get right and in
India to get votes the easiest way to do
that is to polarize the public and then
that's one and number two to give
freebies because the education system in
India is so abysal and pathetic that
people don't realize that freebies will
will not Advance you in life in family
in life in your country but the
education system has ensured that people
remain mentally lobotomized and don't
understand that freebies are bad so the
education system perpetuates this
situation in India where you have to
keep giving freebies to people to get
votes it's a self-perpetuating
cycle and I've been saying for God knows
how long that we should we need to
reform the education system nothing has
been done and you have freebies being
given out by all every political party
doesn't matter which political party it
is um so yes India's politicians don't
they simply cannot afford to look beyond
the upcoming elections it's always
short-term thinking short-term thinging
short-term thinging that's what the
system in India that that exists in
India has been designed to do it's been
designed to keep India a
mediocre nation that doesn't achieve
anything close to what is potential is
and the politicians who are in India who
exist in India and who are in power they
have come to power because of this
system so why will they change it so
because of this political system India
is doomed to continue wallowing in
mediocrity unless there is a leader with
the
coones to to take the system by the
Scruff of its neck and change it but we
don't have any politicians of that of
that stature in India today so that's
where India is today India is going to
continue being the way it is India is
India was
colonized after 1947 India supposedly
got its independence but we have this
system in India which essentially makes
us again colonized you know uh and uh so
you are absolutely right my friend here
I understand why you left India because
of the lack of Merit which is another
tremendous problem in
India you have freebies
and then you
have this system where there is no
respect for merit in this country which
is simply a way of telling people those
of you who can should leave the country
and those of you who can't should remain
behind and try and do rent seeking from
whatever is
left um so yeah we so so the difference
between India and China essentially is
that the Chinese have a centralized
system a one party State a dictatorship
and a ship if you look at all this is
clearly Superior to a democracy
democracy is you going down to the
lowest common
denominator okay dictator a dictatorship
can be good or bad if you have an evil
Tyrant as a dictator it's going to be
bad for the people but if you
have a good person as a dictator a
reasonably good person as a dictator
then your country can achieve things
that that are close to its full
potential and a good example for India
is ashoke ashoke Moria the great emperor
as a person he was not a very nice
person he was a dangerous person to be
near but as an emperor he was one of the
one of the best Emperors we
had so even a tyrant can be great for
the country for the
civilization but that only works in a
dictatorship in democracy it's all about
mediocrity it's all about going all the
way down to the lowest common
denominator which is all this culture of
of non-merit and and freebies so that's
the situation in India today and that's
why everybody wants to leave the country
and how can we blame
them Vikram geopolitical says recent
Oxfam report says that the British
looted $64 trillion worth of money from
the Indian subcontinent what are My
Views yeah so the figure that was out
there earlier was $45 trillion now Oxfam
which is the left leaning organization
by the way it says that the British
looted $64 trillion worth of of value
out of the Indian out of
India now India's
left leaning historians the court
historians who were in favor and Vogue
for the most part of India's post 1947
history what will they do about this
they can't do a thing about this because
Oxfam is a super left leading
organization and they themselves have
put out this figure what are My Views
about this I'm not surprised I won't be
surprised if the actual figure is in
excess of 100 trillion I'm not surprised
at all I will not be surprised if the
actual figure turns out to be in excess
of $100 trillion
worth of today's
money that's how they enriched
themselves the British in the west at
our expense but don't blame them we
should have been strong enough to
resist Krishna ragunath from suam from
Surinam says do you think there are more
undiscovered archaeological sites in the
in the subcontinent with the same age as
the IC the Indus Valley Civilization so
2,000 BC to 3,000 BC or older than
that I think it is um it is reasonably
well known that if you look at the dry
River bed of the sarasvati which uh
starts all the way near the Himalayas
and and it extends all the way into Kat
which is Western India if you look at
the dry riverbed of this great ancient
river which no longer exists mainly
mostly then there are more than 2,000
unexplored archaeological sites along
this Dry River bed of this just one
River okay and there are so many other
archaeological sites in the north and
west part of India and maybe other parts
of India as well so there are thousands
of untouched un unexplored and
undiscovered archaeological sites all
across India maybe tens of thousands and
the oldest Arch archaeological site that
we know of that is a part of the
so-called sarasti synu civilization or
Indus Valley or harapat civilization the
oldest known AR archaeological site is
birana in harana and it's been carbon
dated to about 7,500 BC which is about 9
and a half thousand years before today
okay roughly now if you have thousands
of unexplored archaological sites I can
assure you that some of them are going
to be older than 10,000 years before
today maybe 15,000 before today we
simply haven't even started looking at
them so it's guaranteed you're going to
have thousands of sites which are super
super old maybe more than 10,000 BC
that's guaranteed but the ASI the look I
don't blame the ASI the ASI after all
does whatever the government tells it to
do and it it the ASI archaeological
Survey of India it it uh I think it
comes under the ministry of what culture
or something which is one of the worst
Ministries the worst performing
Ministries in my opinion in this
country but yeah it's guaranteed you
will have thousands of AR archaeological
sites older than 3,000 BC maybe older
than 10,000 BC quite
possible okay um the feminist Slayer
says why did the USSR promise to
transfer cryogenic engine technology to
India for its space program but after
the breakup and Russia's emerg
the decision of the of the technology
transfer was reversed so India and
Russia had this deal that they would
sell us a number of cryogenic engines
and also transfer the technology that's
in the last days of the USSR and then
then the USSR broke up and gorbachov was
ousted and Boris yelen came to power
Boris yelen was a western stoo a US
sto and he did whatever the Americans
told him so that's why they denied India
the technology which forced ISRO to
develop its own cryogenic rocket engine
and we have that now so in a way maybe
it was good for us that we were able to
develop it ourselves obviously it set
our program back by a couple of decades
perhaps that's how it goes so the
Americans arm Twisted Russia
into denying India the technology that's
what
happened Tommy shell says how come the
Anglo-Saxons from their little island
managed to formulate or create the
biggest empire in human history with the
most influence to this date and probably
in the next 1,000 years to come what can
we Indians learn from it and Implement
in our lives collectively getting past
our weak victimhood and divided
mentality okay so today if you look at
Western historians and all that they
will tell you that the West came out on
top okay because of the superiority of
its ideas and values and Rel religion
and culture the West Was Superior all
around and that's why they were able to
conquer the world that's what they will
tell you that's the myth they've conduct
they've created okay and the West is led
by the anglos the Anglo-Saxons the the
english- speaking
world the truth is that the
West conquered the world not because of
the superiority of its culture or ideas
or values or religion or whatever the
West conquered the world world because
of its
superiority in applying systematic
organized
violence that's all that's why they won
the world so what should that's why they
conquered the world so what should India
learn from it we need to be better than
everybody
else in applying systematic organized
violence or at least in being capable of
doing it and countering this that's what
we need to learn uh we still haven't
learned that okay otherwise we would
have the most powerful military in the
world but we haven't learned that
otherwise we would have the most
powerful Air Force in the world we don't
even have the most powerful Air Force in
Asia the Chinese are way better than us
and maybe soon Pakistan will be better
than us so we don't learn from history
we learn but our leaders don't
learn uh yeah so that is what we Indians
can learn from it the west and the
anglos prevailed because they were
better than everybody else they were
best in
applying systematic organized violence
that's why they were able to conquer
India they were able to conquer the
Americas and everything else Africa and
everything
else uh geopolitical dub says can strong
can a strong magnetic field be
generated artificially yes of
course see it's all
about it all boils boils down to
electromagnetic
yeah the that's the electromagnetic
force which has two components
electricity and magnetism so yes a
strong magnetic field can be generated
artificially and to do that you need
something called an electromagnet so in
an electromagnet you have a strong
current a high current flowing through a
coil of wire and this creates a magnetic
field so you have devices like uh MRI
machines okay which use this principle
to produce powerful magnetic fields for
in purposes so that's how it is done so
the the simplest method is to use
something called a solenoid it's a coil
of wire with a high current flowing
through it and you can enhance this by
adding an iron core to amplify the field
so that's how you can create a strong
artificial magnetic field uh using a
solenoid and now there are limitations
because of uh factors like heat
generation when you have a strong
current passing through a wire because
of the resistivity of the wire or the
material of the of the material used in
the coil you're going to have heat
that's generator and eventually it may
cause the material to melt down or burn
down that sort of thing and that's where
super conductivity comes in if you have
uh super conducting magnets then
essentially the the resistance is zero
and then you can have much higher
currents with without significant uh
heat loss so that's something we
discussed I think in in last week's
episode super conductivity so yes
absolutely a strong magnet field can
indeed be generated artificially
yes Arijit banerji says why is the J
joint entrance examination of the iits
the second hardest examination in the
whole world when the old iits don't even
come into the under the top 500 colleges
in the world is the
jeit
overrated this is a classic India
problem you have the G the joint
entrance exam which apparently is the
second hardest examination in the world
and so many students go study for this
and so many of them crack it right so
you clearly have a population that is
super smart super
intelligent and if you crack the je you
get a placement in an Indian Institute
of Technology IIT and none of the iits
is even in the top 500 colleges in the
world so you have a super capable super
smart super intelligent population
bright young
kids and you have a rotten
system
that's that's India today and we could
have done some something about the
rotten system in the past 10 years but
have we we haven't so you have an
extremely capable extremely brilliant
bright capable energetic population
young population it's full of the best
potential in the world and their
potential is being wasted by this rotten
system that's the deal so the je is not
overrated it tells you how bril
brilliant Indians are the iits are
garbage sadly I'm not saying all of them
are garbage I'm sure they have some good
professors maybe maybe 5% of the
professors and staff are are top class
but the facilities are costly
especially the engineering facilities
especially the instruments that you get
you okay in the IIT is there's
tremendous funding you will have five
star quality uh conference rooms you'll
have washrooms in which you they have
spent crores of rupees but if you look
at the lab equipment it's 25 30 years
behind today that's what you will
typically face in an
IIT and it's all it all boils down to
the to the to the bureaucrats and the
and the and the staff that that are in
charge of the decision making in the
budgets in the
iits it's the Indian education system
the academic system is just rotten to
the core okay that's the problem so why
haven't why hasn't our leadership why
haven't our elected leaders changed this
reformed this well I am not the person
who can answer that
question so yeah that's that's India for
you a nation with tremendous unlimited
potential which is which is being which
is being held to Ransom by by the
political class and the mediocre
bureaucrats
Katon
ectron okay that's the I don't know what
it means in Greek but yeah uh says that
I am arit banerji I hope you remember me
I want a serious help from you I in
standard 10 right now my board exams are
approaching ICC board my parents want me
to Ace my board examinations but I
haven't started studying seriously yet I
find studying too boring I can empathize
okay continuing my parents also want me
to to do the I the to do the je
preparation as two guys from my Colony
have got into iits but since I have no
other Talent like Arts music Sports Etc
I have to ultimately abide by my parents
I'm also studying to get good grades and
I'll be doing G E Prep only to get an
IIT degree any suggestions or advice for
me this is a situation that lots of
youngsters find themselves in you are
told by your parents you have to
study study study study you must love
studying you must study 10 hours 12
hours a day and when you ask them why
should I study they'll say You must
study because I am telling you to study
shut up keep quiet and study you must
love studying but you not able to see
why you have to study and what's the
point of studying and what will it what
will it give you if you spend the best
years of your life the formative years
of your life 10 12 15 hours studying in
a day and you don't do anything that at
all that you enjoy you just study stud
what's the point right that that's the
problem that kids face students face and
I completely empathized and at the end
of the day you study so much you got get
a godamn degree from an IIT at the end
of the day you're going to end up being
in some
Corporation obeying orders right that's
the problem India doesn't give you
opportunities at best you can get a good
degree and go abroad and and have a
slightly better life outside of the
country that's the deal so what should
you do you are in standard 10 your board
exam is approaching the thing is this
look you can look at it from two
perspectives first of all if you don't
do well in your 10th standard exam you
will not be able to get into a good
college or whatever okay of course if
you do well in the 12th then you'll be
fine but yeah it makes sense to get good
marks at the 10th standard level so if
you do that if you have a good academic
record 10th and 12th and all that then
you can get into a good college and you
can get a job which is high paying and
good status and all that and if you
don't have a good academic record then
you will not get any of that and you
will have to have a a job that you will
not enjoy that
much so yeah you can let fear motivate
you that if I don't study now if I don't
start studying and if I don't do all
these things like my parents say then I
will not have a good
future I will not have a high paying
salary I won't be able to have three
story Bungalow or you know land rowers
or BMWs or whatever I want get to marry
a good girl or
whatever that's one way of motivating
yourself through fear the other
motivation is you should know what you
want in life hopefully you have some big
dream
and maybe getting those good grades and
all will help you achieve the
dream uh so yeah since I don't know you
personally and I don't know what your
long-term dreams goals objectives are I
can only tell you that one of the
stepping stones in India in today's
system to achieving your big goals and
dreams and and having a good life long
term is to do well in
exams so that's what I would say I would
what is my suggestion to you do what
your parents say they probably right um
I know study is boring and all that but
I'm sure there are certain subjects at
least that you find interesting maybe
you can let that motivate you the point
is you have to do well in studies in the
current system so you have no choice at
the end of the day so I would say
whatever motivates you whatever lights
your fire whether it is the the fear of
not doing well and having a bad life or
the Allure of a great life whatever
motivates you use it as a fuel and get
serious about his studies and go for it
and J prep I mean that from my
perspective J prep is actually fun it's
all science right I I I'm a science guy
I love science solving problems and all
so from my perspective it was fun it
would have been
fun so my advice is get serious study
for your exams do well and have a great
life and uh hopefully you have a great
life when you make a lot of money and
then by a certain age by 30s or whatever
maybe you have made enough money to no
longer have to work and then you can do
something that really really uh is
something that you enjoy so uh you have
to find your motivation you have to find
your fuel you have to have your own big
goals and hopes and aspirations
and yeah you got to study for that all
right that's what I would suggest study
get serious all the
best okay redy says how to read a book
or learn a topic exactly as you said
there's no remember there's no need to
remember everything or anything while
reading I'm simply reading a book like a
novel and I for I forgot
everything next time if I open the same
book I it feels like a new
book if I don't remember anything then
what's the point of reading please
answer it's very confusing
look if you ask me to open a
book which is a textbook for your LLB
course or whatever I may be able to read
the whole book in a day tomorrow morning
when I wake up and I open it it'll be
like a new book to me because I've
absolutely no goddamned interest in LLB
or
law if you ask me to study business law
or whatever same thing it has no
interest for me whatsoever because it
has no relevance to my life okay but if
there is some part of business law or
whatever that is relevant to my life and
my work then I'll certainly be very
interested in it and that portion I'll
read and I'll remember that so my point
is that if you if you are made to read
something that you have absolutely no
interest in then even if you force
yourself to read the entire
book in one day or in three days or
whatever the next time you pick up the
book it'll be like a new book because
nothing was retained because you have no
interest in it there's nothing confusing
about it you'll be able to remember
stuff only if you find it interesting
maybe it's an interesting topic but the
writer has presented it in a very boring
or very confusing way then once again
you won't be able to remember what was
written but if you pick up another book
from a different writer on the same
topic you may be able to remember it so
there are multiple reasons for this one
maybe you're not interested in the topic
at all second maybe the writer is
terrible there are books on physics I've
said I've seen that that were written by
terrible writers what was the guy's name
maybe should learn a guy from I Bombay I
forget his name right now such a
terrible book he wrote about nuclear
physics my God my God so yeah that
happens even if you find the subject
interesting if the writer is terrible
and if it's the presentation is not
logical then you won't remember it so
that's the thing so yeah so you got to
find a solution for your for your
problem understand by by understanding
this all right I think I will now take
some questions from the live chat from
the live chat um so if you have
questions that you would like me to take
please ask me the questions right now in
the live chat and uh let's see ual says
ual MTI says I think India currently has
best Engineers but not scientists we
need Super scientists to become visha
Guru how do you think look Vish Guru
forget about this term visha Guru I
don't like this term visha Guru we are
not even visha student right now that's
how bad we are now coming to the your
point you may be right actually to a
large extent we have extremely good good
good Engineers look at is is the the
people who work at ISRO are not
scientists they're not rocket scientists
they're Engineers but the media says
they're rocket scientists they're not
scientists they're engineers and they
are really high quality Engineers um so
what is engineering engineering is
applied science you apply it in the real
world what is pure science it's
theoretical Einstein Newton uh
Heisenberg schinger all that that's
theoretical physics that's that's real
pure
science um we don't seem to have good
pure scientists right now I
mean can you think of a single uh
breakthrough in science that has come
out of India the past 50 years high
quality we have many
scientists um who teach in various
institutions and all but what is their
contribution to science so you are right
I'll tell you that I I'll tell you what
there are lots of Indian origin
scientists high quality scientists who
are working outside of India so what
once again it comes back to the problem
that we have in India that there is no
merit and the education system is
ghastly and terrible the academic system
is rotten our institutions are are crap
all that so that's why our best minds
they go
abroad uh yeah we do need Super
scientists see you need two things to
become a technological power you need
people who can who can achieve
breakthroughs in pure in the pure
sciences and then there unique people
who can take those those breakthroughs
and apply them in the real world so
that's scientists and Engineers you need
both um and the system that we have the
academic system the higher education
system that we have it is not geared for
doing this our academic system excels at
identifying and destroying Talent OR
forcing it to migrate out of out out of
the country and it only promotes and
respects mediocrity that's the problem
that's what I've been highlighting for
years but um I think our system loves
mediocrity that's why it doesn't change
but you are right ual I I largely agree
with
you all right um geopolitical du says
what is sound sound so sound essentially
at the basic physical level is
vibrations in a
medium vibrations in a medium and if
those if the frequency of those of those
vibrations lies within the auditory
range the audible range of the human
uh human ear then we perceive that as
sound so you make a sound okay you you
snap your fingers it's going to produce
vibrations in the air okay it's going to
vibrate the air this snap now the
frequency of the vibrations because it
falls within the range of our ears
that's why we hear it and this you can
also do it with metal or wood or
whatever with VAR substances so as long
as the vibrations um the frequency is
within the audible range you perceive
that as sound so the the vibrations it
vibrates the air it also vibrates the
air over here and then the vibrations
they they create sympathetic vibrations
in the
eardrum and then there is this entire
apparatus that translates those
vibrations into electrical signals that
are then funneled into the brain and the
auditory cortex or whatever it is it
interprets that as a sound so that is
sound
okay VI manak says can Digital Data be
stored between DNA molecules I think you
can store Digital Data in DNA molecules
not between but in DNA
molecules uh DNA storage you can do it
so in in DNA you typically have the
genome that's encoded in in the DNA and
there are
um and you have all those chemicals a g
ad adenosin tryptophan guine Etc but you
can use that those those configurations
all of that to to conf to store actual
data I mean actual data as in as in data
that's digital you would otherwise
stored digitally or whatever you can
store that in DNA you can do
that um it's possible definitely yes
right
um the chandelas says uh can you explain
time and space in pure in plain English
is time linear cycling look according to
mythology and and culture and Etc
especially the Indian culture you have
the cycle of yugas Etc which is a kind
of a repeating pattern okay and you will
have some scientists who will say that
time is not linearity is cyclic and all
I don't know about that
okay I I don't have that much mental
bandwidth I don't understand that I've
not understood what they've said um but
to answer your question what is time
what is space
in plain simple English it's Dimensions
okay so we know the three dimens you
know physicist will like like doing this
you
know the right hand rude and all that so
you have three dimensions length breadth
and width right length breadth and
height three dimensions let's say you
have a square or a rectangle it has
three dimensions there is length there
is height and there is width
right so that is space
and then there is a fourth dimension
according to general relativity which is
the dimension of time so you can think
of it as four dimensions obviously we
cannot visualize four dimensional space
because we are threedimensional
creatures and we don't perceive time
very very strongly it's kind of vague
the perception of time but in the
simplest way I can explain to you it's
four dimensions and the four dimensions
they together form the fabric of
SpaceTime which is the stage on which
the universe exists and in which things
happen that's what I could tell you in
the simplest possible
way
um runit sahu says can Yogi save us from
being a wasal interesting question you
you asking me
here you know I there's a saying right
what takes you from 1 to
10 cannot take you from 10 to
100 so whatever was able to take you you
were at one and you wanted to reach 10
and you were able to reach
10 whatever it is that took you from 1
to 10 will not be able to take you from
10 to 100 you need something else a
different
solution now what is that solution is a
question what can save India from being
a wasal is also a question over here the
only thing that can save India from
being a wasal is is hard
power now how do you build hard power
you need the right Vision you need the
right right leadership
so leadership is definitely a
factor um can Yogi be the leader who
will give India the kind of hard power
that prevents us from falling into this
wasal trap I don't know one would hope
so but the wasal Trap could happen in
the next one or two years it could
happen right now if Trump tomorrow calls
up hey narandra you got a choice you're
got to make a choice you're either with
me or against me and if if you're
against me I'm going to destroy you and
that's a simple ultimatum and you have
to immediately do what he wants you to
do then Mr Yogi could be five years from
now it's too far
away so we don't know we don't
know for India to not be a wasal you
need to be at least as powerful as China
is right
now China is about three and a half or
four times more powerful than India with
a much better system non-corrupt or less
corrupt system and a system that is
geared towards the national interest in
India it's not our political system is
just it doesn't prioritize the national
interest it's a it's a short-term
worldview that the politicians
have so yeah many problems that India
faces right now uh I would love to have
love to see Mr Yogi being the Prime
Minister
someday uh but maybe it it'll be too far
down the line maybe by the time we may
have become a wasal which may not be a
bad thing for India we have already gone
through a thousand years of History
maybe 100 to two 100 years more who
knows may not be that
bad you know I I would love to say nice
things and be very positive but I better
be honest with you don't you
think
um man cheda says how important is the
10 trillion mark for a nation your
thoughts on the fact that India which
was a Metallurgy Hub can't make steel
for the Cav engine thoughts on Italy
invitation for sixth June I don't know
like three three four questions I'll
I'll take maybe one or two the10
trillion doll Mark is a good
psychological barrier to cross it's like
if you're a cricketer if you're a
batsman if you are out on 100 or 99 or
if you reach 100 it's a big
psychological thing it's just a
difference of one one run right but it's
a huge psychological Mark so if you
reach that that Mark of $10 trillion of
economy then it's it's like huge moral
booster for the people of the country it
brings everyone together it brings huge
wave of of opt optimism and you can do
anything that sort of thing so it's a
great psychological Mark and of course
10 trillion of having an economy of that
size is no is no joke right uh so it's
very important for us right um India was
a mety hub back in the day we were
de-industrialized by the British yes and
now we can make steel for the Cav engine
look
it's um okay I've spoken about the
engine issue a
lot we've got to start a program we got
to sustain it for 20 30 years it takes
time to mature your
technology so um and of course you have
to identify the key technologies that
you need going forward the technologies
that are key to India becoming a great
power you to identify what those are
Materials Science is one of those
artificial intelligence is another
quantum Computing is another Super
Computing is another semiconductors is
another rare earth metals we need access
to those so that so that's a vital thing
lithium is another vital thing of course
energy Independence all those things you
have to identify what is crucial for
your nation and can be a deal breaker in
your becoming a great great power going
forward and then you have to prioritize
those invest in those things and ensure
that the capabili is mature this needs a
long-term Vision when you have
politicians who are looking at the next
five years at at most they will not care
about these things unless you a
Visionary politician but we don't have
those in this country so
sad okay let's take one or two more
questions and then we will be done for
today's episode I don't um what do we
have what do we have lots of
questions
um so we have we have Joe
Rogan welcome sir welcome big fan tell
us about the PD race map did Knights of
Templar travel the world before Columbus
and melan
I'm sorry I don't know what this p p
race map is maybe I will Google it and
find out with you what is p race let's
go and let's go to Google for the last
question for today P
race map let's see I I don't know I've I
don't know about this it was a world map
compiled in 1513 by autom Admiral and
cartographer p a part one3 of this map
survives let's take a look at what it
looks like this map uh let us go to
tools and we will we will say that we
want uh large
images size
large and then we see what does it show
it seems to show interesting stuff does
it show Antarctica ET I think it shows
Antarctica I think I must have come up
across this before it seems to show
Antarctica uh so yeah uh maybe somebody
had discovered Antarctica before
Columbus um we don't know was it the
Knights Templar was it somebody else was
it the Ottomans I don't know but it's
interesting that this map exists and it
seems to
depict depict parts of Antarctica
further down from South America it does
and it's it's from 1513 which is like um
before anybody supposedly discovered
Antarctica big mystery and I don't think
we know we I don't think we know why we
don't know we don't know the answer to
the question right so interesting and uh
big mystery Etc
yeah
um shall we take another
question
um remad says was Hitler a great
leader what do you want me to
say look was he a great leader he
failed and with his failure his country
was destroyed so from that perspective
itself the non-negotiable quality a
leader must have understand this Indians
the one quality that you cannot
negotiate with in a leader the one
quality that is indispens that you need
to have in leader is that a leader must
succeed a leader cannot fail if a leader
fails you have to throw them out you
can't tolerate a leader who fails and we
in India tolerate leaders who fail it's
okay to have some small failures along
the way it's like you want to win the
World Cup but you lost a couple of
matches but at the end of the day if you
can reach the final and win you have
succeeded so some small defeats are fine
some small small failures are fine but
at the end of the day the big objective
you have a leader must achieve a leader
cannot fail and Hitler fails which means
he was a bad leader and that's the end
of end of the story all right with that
we are at the end of today's session
thank you so much for all your questions
it was fun as always and uh we'll
continue doing this next week and we
will have another live stream and I'll
take more of your questions then until
then please take care uh keep asking
questions keep raising your standards
and I will see you very soon next week
take care thank you bye